

GAME PROGRAMMER

Details

Gdańsk

Poland

grzpotry@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Polish

DATE OF BIRTH

1995

Links

LinkedIn

Github

Skills

Unreal Engine / C++

Unity / C#

Gameplay Programming

Networking code

Continous Integration

Performance Optimizations

Git / Perforce

Editor tools

Al - Behaviour Trees & State machines

Procedural Generation

Languages

Polish (native)

English (fluent)

Profile

Over 8 years of experience in game software development as a programmer. In total 8 years in Unity and 2 years in Unreal Engine on which I am recently mostly focused on.

With a wealth of experience in transforming design concepts into gameplay, I thrive when tackling new challenges and realizing ambitious visions.

Consider myself as generalist - extensive experience in a rapidly growing studio required wearing many hats and engaging in various phases of the production, from concept, through rough development - to the final releases and product maintenance.

Employment History

Unreal Engine Programmer - TPP Action rpg project, Event Horizon

JANUARY 2024 - PRESENT

As the most experienced team member in the Unreal ecosystem, I led the development of a new project on Unreal Engine 5.3, focusing on creating a vertical slice for a TPP Action RPG roguelike game centered around combat. My responsibilities included establishing an efficient development environment for the team and developing core features of the early prototype. Key contributions involved:

- Customizing the Lyra Sample project for our specific needs, enabling easy
 reuse and extension of existing systems, and configuring version control for the
 repository.
- Leveraging Modular Game Features to maintain a clean separation between core Lyra foundations and our custom game logic.
- Establishing unified standards eg. for using GAS across the whole team.
- Setting up CI pipelines for automated builds and tests in TeamCity.
- Developing core combat mechanics, including melee attacks, movement with motion warping, basic enemy AI, player skills & controls, and essential application features such as saving and interaction systems.

Senior Unity Programmer - Dark Envoy, Event Horizon

OCTOBER 2019 - JANUARY 2024

PC Release in 10/2023

https://store.steampowered.com/app/945770/Dark_Envoy/

After successful launch of Tower of Time, I started to worked on more ambitious RPG title with multiplayer co-op, procedural content generation, cinematic in-game cutscenes, voice over and much deeper rpg progression mechanics.

Chief technical areas of expertise in this project

- Developed Procedural Content Generation systems (dungeons, loot, quests etc.)
- Leaded enemies AI development, prepared BT tools used by designers
- Integrated and supervised 3rd party tools (eg. visual scripting) for designers
- Collaborated on core combat and guests mechanics
- Supported development of multiplayer features
- Automated build, and testing pipelines by utilizing CI system (jenkins)
- Optimized application performance (CPU, memory, loadings)

Hobbies

Science, Astrophysics, Outdoor, Scuba-Diving, Hiking, Videography, Triathlon, Sci-Fi

Unreal Engine Programmer - Survive the Fall, Angry Bulls Studio

OCTOBER 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

Small part-time order at the early stage of Survive the Fall development.

Worked on core system for setting up gameplay by designers and RTS controls.

Unity Programmer - Tower of Time, Event Horizon

MAY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

PC Release in 04/2018

https://store.steampowered.com/app/617480/Tower_of_Time/

Tower of Time was first project in game dev I've worked on in newly emerging game studio Event Horizon. During that time I was still studying on University so it was part-time job mostly. I was chiefly responsible for gameplay programming and tools in small team of 4 programmers. I led development of exploration & quest features and mentored content creators.

Education

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science, Gdańsk University of Technology

OCTOBER 2014 - FEBRUARY 2018